

#### **PROFILE**

Full stack web developer looking to integrate into an existing, collaborative web development team by leveraging my creativity, organizational acumen, and 10 years of experience as a music educator. Skillfully meeting the needs of students, parents and school administrations simultaneously has given me the advantage of experience in positions that require balancing the needs of multiple clients, both internal and external. Web development has been a passion of mine for several years and I look forward to furthering my experience in the field.

#### CONTACT

PHONE: 210.906.8276

EMAIL:

ogmdeveloper0@gmail.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILES**

PORTFOLIO: oscar-medina.com

Github: /ogmedina

LinkedIn: /oscargmedina

**Attached Project Page** 

# OSCAR MEDINA

Full Stack Web Developer

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Texas in San Antonio Bootcamp– San Antonio, TX**A 24-week intensive program focused on mastering technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars & React.

**Texas A&M University - Kingsville, TX**Bachelor of Music

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### UTSA Bootcamp, Student

2020-2021

Successfully planned and executed multiple programming projects, key completion samples attached.

#### McAllen ISD, Assistant Band Director

2014-2020

Implemented instrumental music curriculum for a 250-plus member band program and outperformed at TMEA Region Band XV and Jazz Band competitions with multiple earned spots including 1st chairs on the instruments of Trumpet, Tuba and Electric Bass.

### La Joya ISD, Head Orchestra Director

2010-2014

Rewrote, implemented, and executed the instrumental music curriculum for the high school orchestra and guitar program in vertical alignment with the teaching cluster.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Languages:

Java Script ES6+ / CSS3 / HTML5 / SQL / NoSQL / React

#### Applications:

GitHub / MongoDB / MySQL

#### Tools:

Node / JQuery / Bootstrap / Express / Handlebars

## **MEAL MAKER**

# github.com/ogmedina/Meal-Maker ogmedina.github.io/Meal-Maker/

- Meal Maker is an app for a user to search for meal and drink recipes. The user is also able to save recipes they have found for later use.
- Responsibilities included writing front and back-end code for food page and designing front end for entire app.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Foundation 6, JS, jQuery, Edamam API, TheCocktailDB API

## STAY-IN-APP

# github.com/ogmedina/project-2 stayingin.herokuapp.com

- The Stay-In-App is an app that lets users find movies and create a watchlist.
- Responsibilities included all back-end code.
- Tools: HTML, Express Handlebars, MySQL, jQuery, Sequelize, PassportJS, FontAwesome, Travis CLI

# **RC SOCIAL NETWORK**

github.com/ogmedina/Rc-Social-Network powerful-journey-56416.herokuapp.com

- Social Environment for RC fans and enthusiasts to post locations, pictures, and descriptions for good areas locally to run RC Vehicles.
- Responsibilities included front/back end throughout, MongoDB database, Cloudinary API Image Uploading, all CSS.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, React, Node, Express, Anime.js, Cloudinary API, JS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap, Bcrypt, Multer, Nodemon, Passport, Cors NPM